so again
shooting for russ mitchell so
i want to make sure i pronounce all the
names correctly so i'm going to take the
option to phone a friend
hello russ
okay here we go i'm just just
apologizing ahead of time
first up we have teresa
he's going to be inducted by andrew
siddinski
andrewski born to ukrainian refugee
parents in innsbruck austria soon after
world war ii he became active in the
defense of soviet bloc political
prisoners including clandestine work
with dissidents behind the iron curtain
smuggling books manuscripts and printing
materials and he's now volunteer
director of the ukrainian museum
archives in cleveland
uh appropriate that tarash magala is the
first to be
[Music]
inducted
he's been a leader
in
nationally
locally in the ukrainian community in
america
and many of you know him
i can't begin
to
uh
talk about teraz in 90 seconds let alone
90 minutes
but i do want to say he he was the
president of the united ukrainian
organizations here in cleveland
he's been active
in american politics
for
good lord from the 50s
he's helped so many people
individually
with their careers including me
but so many others
a highlight
soon after ukraine declared its
independence tadas organized a meeting
in the oval office president
george h.w bush
to recognize ukraine's independence 30
years ago
he represented our country
uh at the dedication of the baby
dedication in ku
he's the long he was the long time
president of the ukrainian
museum archives and director
and
what else can i say
my good friend
i once looked upon him as my
surrogate father now i look at him as my
brother
and on behalf of
all the so many many
friends and admirers that us
congratulations
you're a wonderful
my honor
[Applause]
oh
i have seen this
many many times
it's it's just
what a what a what a great
situation that we had right in this area
right in cleveland
right in ohio
and we've done
a real good
[Applause]
i thank all of you
that
are here
some for me
and
lots from others
and that's wonderful
and
keep it up
hopefully
thank you thank you thank you
you